(Translated) Alas!
Đáng...tiếc...
Two loving souls by death cruelly parted
Cánh hạc đơn lẻ khó thành đôi
In madness and grief, a dark path started
Si nhân si oán hận mê cuồng
Calamity was drawn, rituals subverted
Chỉ vì tế lễ gây tai họa
But by her cold steel was death averted
Mỹ nhân rút kiếm cứu chúng sinh
Mortal ties broken, with the adepti she went
Duyên phàm mông lung tiên duyên đậm
Their abiding place filling paternal bonds rent
Thiên luân tiêu tán ghé phủ tiên
To her red strings of binding they sent
Tơ hồng trói buộc tâm tà niệm
And they dwelt long together, content
Dấu tích trên tuyết vẫn in hằn
The crane returned to a home without luster
Hạc về không còn trông thấy tổ
The cobwebs overgrown, the grave-shrouds a-fluster
Tơ nhện giăng kín lá cờ xưa
But one bond upon her
Hồng trần nhân quả đã trôi xa
This world could not muster
Khói tan
Thus does the Divine Damsel's tale duly end
Vốn dĩ "Thần Nữ Hủy Diệt" đến đây đã sắp kết thúc
But today a new tale I have to append
Nhưng hôm nay tôi xin phép thêm vài câu
Which I shall now tell — if you shall attend
Biểu diễn cho các vị nghe
From the world she seems apart
Khúc hát cao điệu chưa chắc không người hiểu
But there are those who know her heart
Tự có tri âm và thanh từ
With crimson spear and flashing brand
Hồng anh phấp phới kiếm lưu tinh
To still the raging tides they stand
Trực chỉ nộ triều tẩy hải thanh
The crane once returned
Giờ đây hạc quay về
And once, she was spurned
Trời đất bao la không chỗ tựa
She turned, and left alone
Cô độc rời đi
With friends all around
Bạn mới người xưa ngồi đầy sảnh
To whom she is bound — a home
Cùng nhau hội tụ khoảnh khắc này